phplist.com 2015-03-19

# Privacy Policy : phpList

Below is our privacy policy for the personal information we collect from you and how we safeguard and protect that information. PhpList Hosted (beta) is part of phpList Hosted services, offered by phpList Ltd through www.phplist.com. The companies registered address is Kneath Point, a Flitton Rd, Greenfield, Bedfordshire, MK45 5DJ United Kingdom. Company Number is 07582966. 

## The information we collect and how we use it

Wherever 'phpList Hosted' is mentioned, it includes the beta version, phpList Hosted (beta). 

#### Your name and contact details

When you sign up for a PhpList Hosted (beta) account, subscribe to our newsletter or contact our support team, you provide us with information such as your name, email address, organisation and a password. By providing us with this information, you consent to your information being collected, used and stored by us in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

We use this information to create and secure your PhpList Hosted account to make sure only you can access your installation. We will also use it to contact you on your account situation (activation, upgrading, suspending, make inactive, closure) as well as on payments and subscriptions. 

We will use the information to send you so-called system-alert messages to inform you on planned maintenance work, system improvements, version updates and other customer service information. Additionally, we may use your contact data to send you updates on our latest services and products or to contact you so we can learn more about our clients. 

We may also use your personal data to analyse visitors' behavior on our website in order to improve our website and services. We may also share aggregate information (without revealing any individual data) with third parties which offer their services through our website. For similar purposes, we may send you a short survey to obtain your feedback on our products and services. 

We may use your contact information to inform you about changes in the PhpList Hosted service, Terms & Conditions, Anti-Spam Policy or this Privacy Policy. 

#### Information you supply in transactions

Where you supply us with personal and financial information (such as your credit card or bank details), we may use this information to process the related payments that derive from our business relationship with you and which have been authorised by you.

#### Information of your campaigns and subscribers

When you create a campaign or a distribution list using PhpList Hosted, we have access to the data on your list and the information in your campaign. 

This information is used to provide you with PhpList Hosted, such as sending the messages to your subscribers and track open and click data on your campaigns. Apart from providing you with statistics on your campaign (total number of messages sent, bounces, unsubscribes, open and click rates) we may also aggregate the data to collect and analyse this information for the total of our clients. Furthermore we may use this information to verify compliance with the Terms and Conditions.

#### Disclosure to third parties

We may be required to disclose information to legal authorities if they so request it and when they have the proper authorisation, such as a search warrant or court order. It may also be seen by our auditors and professional advisors solely for their professional purposes.

#### Retention of personal information

We will retain your information for the period we are legally obliged to do so and for as long as your account is active with us and then for a further 90 days.

#### Protection of your personal information

We are concerned with safeguarding your personal information and the details of any transactions. We have appropriate organisational and technical security measures in place to protect your data against unauthorised disclosure or processing. 

#### Controlling your personal data

If your personal details change (including, but not limited to, a change in your email address), you are responsible for notifying us of those changes so that we can keep your records up-to-date. You can adapt the personal details we keep of you by clicking the preferences link in any email communication you receive from us. 

You can opt out of any email marketing communications from us by clicking the unsubscribe link of the last email you have received from us. 

#### Changes to this statement

phpList's Privacy Policy is subject to change at any time. Changes to the policy will be notified on the website prior to implementing any mayor changes.
